Guide to the Labor Theater Records WAG.033
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Labor Theater Records
1959-1986
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Labor Theater (New York, N.Y.)
Craig, Bette
Portz, C. R.
WAG.033
12.5 Linear Feet in 13 record cartons.
This collection contains the records of the Labor Theater (1973-1987?), which was a theater group that worked to bring plays to the American working class. The collection contains correspondence, grant proposals, and confirmations, by-laws, reports, contracts, touring agreements, theater locations, resumes, programs, scripts, press reviews, questionnaires, photographs, and financial records that relate to the fundraising and productions of the Labor Theater.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Labor Theater was founded in 1973 by Bette Craig and Chuck Portz to provide theater to working class people and produce plays based on contemporary social and economic problems. Craig and Portz were given a grant from the endowment for the Arts in 1978, which allowed them to travel to England and explore the labor theater community there. The Theater was at its most active in the early 1980s, producing plays such as "Bandits," "Jack London," "The Bottom Line," "Ragged Trousered Philanthropist," and others, often written by Portz and Craig. In addition to working out of their permanent location in New York (336 W.20th Street), the theater also toured around the country from early in its inception. The Theater received funding by both endowment funds and labor unions, like the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers and the International Ladies Garment Workers Union. By 1987, the Labor Theater turned into Realization Productions.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into four series:
Series I: General
Series II: Productions
Series III: Unprocessed Materials
Series IV: Photographs
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, grant proposals, and confirmations, by-laws, reports, contracts, touring agreements, theater locations, resumes, programs, scripts, press reviews, questionnaires, and photographs. These materials reflect the establishment, development, and operations of The Labor Theater since its foundation by Bette Craig and Chuck Portz in 1973. Photographs in this collection consist mostly of headshots and production stills. The Labor Theater's relationship with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union, St. Peter's Performing Arts Center, and the American Theater Association is reflected in these records. A large portion of Series III is related to funding, fundraising, and other financial records of the Theater.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Bette Craig and Charles Portz in 1985. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1985.016, 1985.017, NPA.2000.302 and NPA.2008.009.
Separated Materials
Seven cans of partially edited footage of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers Union, filmed in 1974, were separated to the Tamiment/Wagner Moving Images Collections under the tape numbers 254-260. (FILMS 001).
Photographic prints.; Questionnaires.; Motion pictures.; Programs (documents); Working class -- United States.; Labor Theater (New York, N.Y.); St. Peter's Performing Arts Center; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; Portz, Chuck; Craig, Bette; American Theatre Association; Craig, Bette; Portz, C. R.; Labor Theater (New York, N.Y.)
- Series I: General, 1959-1986; 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Advisory Board: Minutes, 1977-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Affiliate Artists, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AFL-CIO Labor Parts: Correspondence, Program, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTNU), Humanities: Correspondence, Proposal, Project, 1978-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Theatre Association, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Audience Response: Letters, Surveys, Spring Tour, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Auditors Reports, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Banner Theater (England) Script, Fliers, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors: Meetings and Minutes, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bookings, Correspondence, Fliers, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bookings: Correspondence, Fliers, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bookings: Correspondence, Fliers, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - British American Repertory Theater: Brochures, Press Release, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - British Equity: Sample Contract, Schedule, Minutes, Journal, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women: Reports, Newspapers, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, General, 1973-1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Cultural Assistance Center: Printed Materials, Attendance List, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Fried, Emmanuel: Correspondence, Programs, Fliers, Printed Material, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Funding, CETA: Applications, Correspondence, Fliers, Scripts, Title IV., 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Funding, Ethnic Proposal: Application, Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Funding, Grant Proposal: Made in USA, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Funding, Labor Institute for Human Enrichment, Health and Safety Show: Correspondence, Proposal, Script Outlines, Safety Cuts, 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Funding, NEH Grant for Touring Ragged Trousered Philanthropists, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Funding, National Endowment for the Arts, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Funding, National Endowment for the Arts, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Funding, National Endowment for the Arts, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Funding, National Endowment for the Arts (Media), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Funding, National Endowment for the Arts, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Funding, NYSCA: Applications, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Funding, PA Council on the Arts Grants, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Harlan County Film: Promotion, Correspondence, Press Releases, Reviews, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Heating: Correspondence, Agreement, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - History of the Labor Theater: Profiles, Printed Materials, 1977-1984 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Interaction Program, England: Brochures, Fliers, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Iron Clad Agreement Re Out Of This Furnace: Press Releases, Correspondence, Fliers, Publicity, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Labor and the Arts: Correspondence, List of Plays, Fliers, Organizations, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Lincoln Center Library: Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - National Congress of Neighborhood Women: Correspondence, Fliers, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - National Theater, England: Programs, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Off-Off Broadway: Correspondence, Agreement, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Paramount Picture Corporation: Lease, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Permission to Perform: Correspondence, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Playwrights: Correspondence, 1973-1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Political and Working Class Theater, England: Documents, Report, Article, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Program Setups, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Projects, The Acting Practicum: Correspondence, Press Release, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Projects, ACWA Oral Histories: Interviews, Memorandum, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Projects, All Crafts Community Theater: Report, Agreement, Booklet, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Projects, Chelsea History Workshops: Correspondence, Program, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Projects, Childrens Theater, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Projects, Ellis Island: Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Projects, Ethnic Theater: Reference Material Correspondence, Memorandum, Fliers, Pamphlets, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Projects, Federal Theater, George Mason University Correspondence, Scripts, Fliers, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Projects, Films: Proposal, Correspondence, Fliers, Press, 1978-1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Projects, National Park Service: Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Projects, National Restaurant: Correspondence, Coupon, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Projects, Production Considerations: Correspondence (Miscellaneous), 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Projects, Smithsonian: Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Projects, Workshops: Correspondence, Printed Material, Fliers, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Projects, WPA/Radio-NEH Correspondence, Scripts (Peggy Farber), 1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Publicity: Early Pieces, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Publicity: General, 1976-1984 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Record of Performances: Notes, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Rejected Scripts: Correspondence, Fliers, 1973-1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Resume, Administrator, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Resumes, Choreographers/Directors: Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Resumes, Miscellaneous: Correspondence, News Release, 1974-1980 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Resumes, Set, Lighting, Costume Designers: Correspondence, Printed Material, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Resumes, Stage Managers/Technicians: Correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Sanctuary Theatre, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Script: Miscellaneous (never performed), Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Script: Miscellaneous (never performed), undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Shared Season, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Shared Season, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Shared Season, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Skylight Pictures, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Songs, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - St. Peters Performing Art Center: Benefit - Correspondence, Fliers, Press List, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - St. Peters Performing Art Center: City Youth Theater: Fliers, Correspondence, Proposal, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - St. Peters Performing Art Center: Contracts, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - St. Peters Performing Art Center, Dept. of Cultural Affairs: Application, Correspondence, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - St. Peters Performing Art Center, Film Program: Miscellaneous Fliers, Press Releases, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - St. Peters Performing Art Center: Minutes, Board Meetings, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - St. Peters Performing Art Center: Minutes, Brochures, Newsletters, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - St. Peters Performing Art Center: Minutes, By-Laws, Certificate of Incorporation, Grant Applications, Agreements, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - St. Peters Performing Art Center Rentals: Contracts, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - St. Peters Performing Art Center Vestry Board: Schedule, Proposals, Membership, Correspondence, Memorandum, Brochure, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Sue, Peggy Ewan McColl, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - TACT Performance Conference: Schedule, Report, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Theater Groups, Scotland, England: Report, Survey, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Theater, Mercyside Unity (England): Playbills, Brochures, Scripts, Fliers, 1959-1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Theater Materials (England, Scotland): Playbills, Programs/1., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Theater Materials (England, Scotland): Playbills, Programs/2., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Theater Materials (England, Scotland): Playbills, Programs/3., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Torn, Rip, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Touring Shows: Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Touring Shows: Press Releases, 1973-1979 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Touring Shows: Itineraries, Press Releases, Programs, Agreement, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Trade Union Studies Program (England): Publicity, Report, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Trucking Industry, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Twentieth Century Trade Union Woman Oral History Project, 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Union Auditoriums, Undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - US/UK Bicentennial Exchange Fellowship: Agreement, Correspondence, Program, Report, News article, Printed Material, Theater Listings, Maps, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Victoria Theater (England) Correspondence, Programs, Proposals, Clippings, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Series II: Productions, 1972-1984; 2
  - 200 RMP: Equity, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - 200 RMP: Finances, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - 200 RMP: Publicity, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - 200 RMP: Script, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - 200 RMP: Tours, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Bandits: Finances, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Bandits: Production, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bandits: Publicity, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Bandits: Script, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bayside Boys: Finances, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Bayside Boys: Production, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Bayside Boys: Publicity, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Bayside Boys: Script, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The Bottom Line: Equity, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - The Bottom Line: Finances, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - The Bottom Line: Production, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - The Bottom Line: Publicity, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - The Bottom Line: Record Album, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - The Bottom Line: Script, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - The Bottom Line: Tour, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - The Bottom Line: Tour, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - The Bottom Line: Tour/England, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - The Bottom Line: Tour/Florida, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - C.A.S.T.: Publicity, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - C.A.S.T.: Spring Tour, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Dont Cry, Child, Your Father's In America: Production, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Dont Cry, Child, Your Father's In America: Publicity, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Dont Cry, Child, Your Fathers In America: Script, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Dont Cry, Child, Your Father's In America: Tour, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Dont Cry, Child, Your Fathers In America/Bintel Brief: Finances, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Dont Cry, Child, Your Father's In America/Bintel Brief: Funding, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Dont Cry, Child, Your Father's In America Bintel Brief: Legal, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Dont Cry, Child, Your Father's In America Bintel Brief: Symposium, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Dying to Make It: Advisory Board and Preliminary Script, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Dying to Make It: Script, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dying to Make It: Script Early Versions [Titled as The Health and Safety Show and Safety Man, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Dying to Make It: Script Revisions, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Dying to Make It: Tour, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Dying to Make It/ Full Confessions of A Socialist: Finances, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Dying to Make It/ Full Confessions of A Socialist: Production, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Dying to Make It/ Full Confessions of A Socialist: Publicity, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Full Confession of A Socialist, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Jack London: Equity (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Jack London: Finances, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Jack London: Production, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Jack London: Publicity, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Jack London: Publicity-Reviews, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Jack London: Script, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Jack London: Tour/San Francisco, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - I Just Wanted Someone to Know: Correspondence, 1978-1985 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - I Just Wanted Someone to Know: Production, 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - I Just Wanted Someone to Know: Publicity, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - I Just Wanted Someone to Know: Script, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - I Just Wanted Someone to Know: Tour, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - I Just Wanted Someone to Know: Tour/2, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - I Just Wanted Someone to Know: Tour/Equity, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Left Out Lady: Production, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Left Out Lady: Publicity, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Left Out Lady: Script, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Mother Jones: Production, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Mother Jones: Publicity, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Mother Jones: Scripts and Revisions, Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Night Shift: Author, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Night Shift: Equity, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Night Shift: Finances, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Night Shift: Production, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Night Shift: Publicity, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Night Shift: Publicity/2, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Night Shift: Script, Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Nostalgia for the Future: Publicity, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - A Peaceable Kingdom: Production, 1980-1984 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - A Peaceable Kingdom: Publicity, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Power: Background Research, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Power: Discussion Program, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Power: Equity, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Power: Finances, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Power: Grant Applications, Project Descriptions, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Power: Production, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Power: Publicity, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Power: Script and Score, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Power: Tour, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Ragged Trousered Philanthropists: Equity, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Ragged Trousered Philanthropists: Finances, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Ragged Trousered Philanthropists: Production, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Ragged Trousered Philanthropists: Publicity, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Ragged Trousered Philanthropists: Script, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Ragged Trousered Philanthropists: Tour, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Railroad Bill: Finances, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Railroad Bill: Production, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Railroad Bill: Publicity/1, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Railroad Bill: Publicity/2, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Railroad Bill: Script, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Railroad Bill: Tour, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Railroad Bill: Tour/2, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Re-Po: Production, Finances, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Re-Po: Publicity, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Singly None: Production, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Singly None: Publicity, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Singly None: Publicity/Reviews, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Singly None: Script, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Singly None: Tour, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Staus: Script, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Why I left California: Finances, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Why I left California: Publicity, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - The Wobblies: Publicity, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - The Wobblies Script, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Working Our Way Down: Publicity, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Working Our Way Down: Script, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Series III: Unprocessed Materials
  - Agreement-Steffie Yost, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Business: Fanfare, Lease for Space (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Materials for the Arts, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Labor Theater Archives, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - New York Telephone, 1981-1983 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Pauline Newman (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Nicaraguan Contribution, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Business Release Forms (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Business Resumes (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Business Safeguard (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Business Advisory Board (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Business Audit, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Business Audit, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Business Audit, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Business Audit, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Business Audit, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Business Auditors' Report, Jun 30, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Business Audit, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report Budgets, 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Signed Contracts (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Background Info Labor Theater (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Business Box Office Forms (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Business Bulk Mail Permit (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Business College of New Rochelle (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Business Contracts/Playwrights (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Business Contracts (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence-General (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Business Equity Deputy and Forms (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Equity Tour, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Equity, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Equity Pension and Welfare Reports, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Equity, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Equity, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Equity Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Equity Tour, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Federal Writers Project (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Kellogg International Program (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Labor Institute of Public Affairs (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Why I Left California-Florida (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Why I Left California-Equity (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Why I Left California-Production (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - The Wobblies (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - The Wobblies-Ticket Sales (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Working Our Way Down Tour New York Bookings (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Working Our Way Down Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Working Our Way Down 1980 Performance Programs (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Working Our Way Down Historical Sources (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Working Our Way Down Hudson Guild (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Federal Theatre Project Scripts (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Funding UAW NEA/NEH Tour, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Funding NEA UAW and ACTWU Pilot Touring, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Funding Mid-Atlantic Regulations Pilot Touring Program (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Funding Joint Foundation Support (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Funding Grants (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Cultural Affairs Department, Community Arts Development Program, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Rutgers Labor Education Center, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - United Church Board of homeland Ministries (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Department of Cultural Affairs-New York City (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Funding: Woody Guthrie Foundation (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Funding-Youth Projects (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Big Bill (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - John McGrath (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - NEH Application, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Funding: New Jersey Council for the Humanities (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - NEH Samples (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Theaterwork, May-Jun 1982 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Platform: New Perspectives on Theatre Today, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Slab Boys Script, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Workers' Theater by Richard Stourac (Manuscript) (Box 15, Folder 5-6, Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Federal Theatre Radio by Edna R. Jackson, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Federal Theatre Review (October 1935-January 1939) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Federal Theatre Magazine, Vol. 2, Num. 5, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Arnold Wesker's Centre 42, 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Union Town: A Labor History Guide to Detroit (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - New York Council Humanities, My Man Bovanne (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - New York Council for the Humanities, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - New York Council for the Humanities, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - New York Council for the Humanities, Evaluation, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - New York Historical Resources Center (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - NYSCA, 1985-1987 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - NYSCA, 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - NYSCA, 1981-1984 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Funding: North Star Foundation (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Pennsylvania Humanties Council Loose Papers (Box 10)
  - Funding: Pennsylvania Humanities Council (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Tennessee State Council, Tour "I Just" (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Staus Pennsylvania Tour Itineraries (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Pennsylvania Humanities Council, Staus Tour Bookings (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Funding Rockefeller Foundation (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - NEA, Arts Exposure, Expansion Arts, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - NEA, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - NEA, Small Professional, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Funding NEA, Original Worksheets, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - NEA, Work Internship (Box 10, Folder 19)